（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
そうやって依存したまま
捨てられて死んでいくんだ
You're going to die, abandoned and waiting.
Four days. August 15th.
４日後 ８月15日
お前の死は
この世界によって決められている
The world itself has decided that you will die.
It's inevitable,
避けられやしない
but I won't let it happen.
だが 俺はそんなの ごめんだ
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）ん…
（岡部）俺は世界にあらがう
I'll fight the world,
まゆりを
必ず救ってみせる
and I will save Mayuri!
ハッ
The coin locker...
（萌郁）コインロッカー
ハッ？
in front of the Daibiru.
大ビル前
ＩＢＮ5100
The IBN 5100...
～
Finalize
Apoptosis
Okabe, what's wrong?
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）
岡部　どうしたの？
（岡部）ハアッ ハアッ
Okay! This'll...
よし これで…
ストップ！
Stop!
The IBN 5100 is in a coin locker.
コインロッカーに
ＩＢＮ5100が？
Moeka told me it hasn't been recovered yet.
（岡部）萌郁が白状した
まだ回収されていないようだ
…で？
So?
What else?
（岡部）決まってるだろう
こいつでロッカーをぶち壊して…
I'll break the locker open with this!
Calm down.
落ち着いて　よく思い出して
Remember.
Remember what?!
何をだ
Everything that's happened.
今までのこと
Despite all the D-mails you've undone,
（紅莉栖）
何度 Ｄメールを取り消しても
ＩＢＮ5100は手に入らなかった
you haven't recovered the IBN 5100.
ああっ
Most likely, it'll be impossible until you get back
多分 元の世界線に戻らないかぎり
無理なんだと思う
to the original world line.
そして そのためには
順番どおりにやるしかない
And for that to happen, you have to do things in order.
あっ…
（岡部）ハア… くっ…
フウ…
すぐ目の前にあるっていうのに
It's so close.
But now, we have a clue.
（紅莉栖）
少なくとも手がかりは つかんだ
ん？
Kiryuu Moeka will do whatever this FB says, right?
桐生萌郁は ＦＢっていう人の
命令なら従うのよね？
And FB's the Rounders' leader, right?
その人が
ラウンダーの指揮官なんでしょ？
Then...
だったら…
ハッ
If I stake out the IBN 5100, maybe I'll see her.
（岡部）ＩＢＮ5100を
見張っていれば
接触できるかもしれない
（岡部）ん？
何しに来た
What are you doing here?
Bread
I want to see FB too.
私もＦＢに会いたい
Didn't you want to avoid seeing her
会いたくないんじゃなかったのか？
会えば幻滅させると
because she'd hate you or something?
I want to know the truth.
確かめたい　本当のこと
What good will it do you?
（岡部）確かめてどうする
I don't know.
分からない
Did you think I'd work with you?
俺が お前と一緒に
行動すると思ったのか？
Well, I guess I can talk to you.
まあ 話が
通じないやつではないか
（紅莉栖）はあ？
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）あ… どうしたの？
What's wrong?
N-Nothing.
（紅莉栖）ああ な… 何でもない
You're with Kiryuu Moeka?
桐生萌郁と一緒にいる？
どうして そうなるの
Why?
She's...
だって その人は…
That's just how it worked out.
（岡部）とにかく そういうことだ
何か動きがあったら連絡する
If something happens, I'll tell you.
（紅莉栖）あっ ちょっとコラ
Hey, wait!
まったく
Geez...
（まゆり）オカリン？
Was that Okarin?
えっ？ うん
Yeah.
（まゆり）ふう…
What's wrong?
（紅莉栖）どうしたの？
I feel like, lately, Okarin and I haven't talked at all.
（まゆり）なんだか最近―
全然 オカリンと お話しして
ないような気がするなって
（天王寺 綯(てんのうじなえ)）
あっ まゆりお姉ちゃん
Big Sis!
はっ 綯ちゃん
Nae!
トゥットゥルー
Hi there, Assistant Big Sis!
助手のお姉ちゃんも
トゥットゥルー
（紅莉栖）ハア…
“紅莉栖お姉ちゃん”ね
It's Big Sis Kurisu.
（天王寺裕吾(ゆうご)）おう
あ… どうも
昨日は すみませんでした
Hi there.
Sorry about yesterday.
（天王寺）岡部に家賃
５千円アップって伝えといてくれ
Tell Okabe his rent's going up 5,000 yen.
I-I will.
あ… はい
Actually, I haven't seen him today.
そういや あの野郎
今日は見なかったな
Did he get sick or something?
体でも壊したか？
バカはカゼひかねえって言うけどな
Although, they say idiots don't get sick.
あ… 実験に使う道具を
探し回ってるみたいで
I think he's looking for stuff to use in his experiments.
Experiments, huh?
実験ねえ
…ったく幸せな野郎だぜ
What a lucky guy.
えっ？
He's a student with his own damn room,
学生風情が
部屋なんぞ借りて―
has friends like you guys,
あんたらみたいな仲間がいて
好き勝手やって フッ
and can do whatever he wants.
ホント幸せだぜ　だがよ
He really is lucky.
But...
Daddy, if we don't hurry, we'll miss the clearance sale!
お父さん　早くしないと
タイムサービス終わっちゃうよ
フッ
よーし　行くか 綯
Right! Let's go, Nae!
うん　バイバイ お姉ちゃんたち
Bye-bye, my big sisters!
Bye-bye!
バイバーイ
（天王寺）今日の夕飯 何がいい？
What do you want for dinner?
（綯）んー えっとねえ…
Um...
（２人）フフッ
A message from FB?
ＦＢからのメールか？
うん
Can I see it?
（岡部）見てもいいか？
えっ？
ん…
ハア…
“Ｍ４(フォー)の判断は―”
"I think M4 was right."
〝正しかったと
思っているわ〞
〝正直な話 Ｍ４ほど
ひたむきに―〞
"To be honest, no one works as hard as M4."
〝頑張ってくれる人は
いないわね〞
Ｍ４？
M4?
That's the code name FB gave me.
（萌郁）
ＦＢがつけてくれたコードネーム
Only FB and I know it.
ＦＢと私しか知らない
It's a secret.
秘密の…
"That's true."
“あなたは確かに 人づきあいが
苦手かもしれないわね”
"You may be bad at social interactions, M4,
“Ｍ４　でも それは あなたの
個性とも言えるんじゃないかしら”
but that's part of what makes you you."
A mom, huh?
おふくろさんか
（萌郁）ん…
（萌郁）
間違いない　ＩＢＮ5100
That's it,
the IBN 5100!
Then is he FB?
（岡部）じゃあ あいつがＦＢか？
違う
No.
FB is a woman.
（萌郁）ＦＢは女の人
ああっ
I know him!
あいつ…
（男性１）
今日 このあとバイトなんだよね
（男性２）そいつはキツいね
（発車ベル）
ああっ
ハアッ　くっ
Damn it!
しまった　くっ…
うう… あっ
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
あとで説明する
I'll explain later.
（岡部）ん？
えっ？
（岡部）ミスターブラウン…
Mister Braun?
Have you driven since you got your license?
（岡部）ちなみに運転は？
No.
（萌郁）ペーパー
Please drive safely.
（岡部）安全運転で頼む
Have you ever seen him before?
（岡部）あの男に見覚えは？
No.
見たことない
What does this mean?
どういうことだ
Four days. August 15th.
（岡部）４日後 ８月15日
The world itself has decided that you will die.
お前の死は
この世界によって決められている
It's inevitable.
避けられやしない
It's on a plane to France,
フランス行きの飛行機…
ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)がある国か
SERN's country of origin.
We never saw any women who could've been FB.
ＦＢらしき女は現れなかったな
（萌郁）ん…
連絡くらいしろ
At least give me a damn phone call!
I was busy.
（岡部）
こっちも立て込んでいたんだ
私はいい　でも…
It's not about me,
but...
Mayuri...
まゆりには…
あっ
そういえば もうずいぶん
話していないような気がする
Come to think of it,
I think it's been a long time since we last spoke.
That's what she also said.
あの子も そう言ってた
すまない
I'm sorry.
うっ…
行くぞ
Let's go.
（紅莉栖）えっ？
直接 当たってみるしかない
We'll have to ask him directly.
当たってみるって？
Ask him?
俺たちがよく知っている人間にだ
He's someone we know very well.
（玄関チャイム）
（天王寺）ん？
（天王寺）
ああ　どうした 朝っぱらから
What brings you here so early?
ん？ まあ上がれや
Well, come in.
（天王寺）…で？ 何の用だ
So, what do you want?
早速 値上げした分の家賃
６千円 払いに来たってか？
Did you come to pay the extra 6,000 yen I added to your rent?
おいおい　そこは おめえ―
Come on now. You're supposed to say,
“千円 増えてるじゃないですか”
って突っ込むところだろ
"That's 1,000 more yen than you said!"
お聞きしたいことがあります
There's something I'd like to ask you.
何だよ 改まって
What? Why so formal?
You know someone named FB, don't you?
ＦＢという人物について
ご存じですね？
We saw it all,
俺たちは全部 見ていたんです
including the IBN 5100 being taken from here.
ここからＩＢＮ5100が
運ばれるのも
We don't care about you.
あなたをどうこうする気はない
We just want to see FB.
俺たちは
ただＦＢに会いたいんです
教えてください
いったい どこにいるんですか？
Please tell me where she is.
You sold us out, M4.
裏切ったようだな　Ｍ４
ハッ
That's the code name FB gave me.
ＦＢがつけてくれたコードネーム
ＦＢと私しか知らない秘密の…
Only FB and I know it.
まさか
Don't tell me—
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
Ever heard of Ferdinand Braun?
（天王寺）フェルディナント･
ブラウンって知ってるか？
The Nobel laureate who invented the Braun tube.
ブラウン管を発明した
ノーベル物理学者？
さすがだな　その頭文字は？
That's the guy.
And what are his initials?
Ｆ… Ｂ…
FB.
（岡部）じゃあ あなたが…
Then you're...
ハッ そんなのウソ…
That can't be true!
Do you just follow blindly and avoid reality?
依存の次は 現実逃避か
Nae is asleep.
綯が寝ている　場所を変えよう
Let's go somewhere else.
This town keeps changing.
（天王寺）この町も
どんどん変わっていきやがる
（萌郁）本当にＦＢ？
Are you really FB?
Yes.
（天王寺）ああ
But those messages...
（萌郁）でも メールは…
（天王寺）全部 俺が書いた
I wrote them all.
（萌郁）ハッ…
Why did I write like a woman?
（天王寺）なんで女言葉かって？
お前をだますためさ
To trick you.
（萌郁）そんな…
（天王寺）お前だけじゃないぜ
Bu—
You weren't the only one.
ほかのやつらにも―
I message others too,
そいつが求めている人物像で
メールを送ってやるんだ
all under the guise of whomever they needed the most.
もっとも お前みたいなやつが
一番だましやすくて助かるがな
Of course, people like you are the easiest to trick, which helps.
（萌郁）ハッ…
Why break off contact with her?
彼女との連絡を絶ったのは？
The second she found the IBN 5100, I didn't need her anymore,
ＩＢＮ5100を手に入れた時点で
そいつは用済みさ
so I cut off contact.
だから捨てた
ダイレクトメールで
メンバーを集めんだよ
We collect members through text messages.
People like that are the easiest to deal with
そういうやつらは扱いやすい
用が済めば始末もしやすい
and the easiest to get rid of when we're done.
They don't belong anywhere.
もともと居場所がねえような
やつらだからな
あなたが
ＳＥＲＮの犬だったなんて
I can't believe you're SERN's dog.
犬？
Dog?
鈴羽(すずは)は… 橋田 鈴(はしだすず)さんは―
Suzuha...
Hashida Suzu didn't take care of you for that!
そんなことをさせるために
あなたの世話をしたんじゃない
（天王寺）お前 なんで
鈴さんのこと知ってる
How do you know about Suzu?
Suzu has nothing to do with this.
鈴さんには関係ねえ
鈴さんには関係ねえことだ
Nothing at all!
But...
（岡部）だが…！
（天王寺）お前たちに何が分かる！
What do you know?!
（２人）ハッ
フッ
Ever sleep in a manhole in the middle of winter?
（天王寺）真冬のマンホールの中で
寝たことあるか？
I was still a kid.
まだ ガキだった
The concrete was so cold that it seeped into your bones.
コンクリが冷たくてな
骨にしみやがる
I didn't eat for three or four days at a time.
３日も４日も何も食べねえで―
And when I laid down,
ずっと横になってると
来やがるんだよ
they came.
（紅莉栖）えっ？
Rats. They thought I was dead and came to eat me.
ネズミが死体と間違えて
かじりに
（２人）ハア…
そんなときさ
糸が垂れてたんだ
But then, I saw a thread descend,
as thin as a spider's.
クモの糸
そしたら登るしかねえだろ
たとえ行き着いた先で―
I had no choice but to climb it.
Even if, by the top, I'd end up dirtying my hands.
この手を汚すことに
なったとしても
そうやって糸を登って
気が付いたら操り人形だ
I kept climbing the thread.
Before I knew it, I was a puppet on a string.
逃れることなんか できねえ
I couldn't escape.
The puppets who do escape the thread,
糸から逃れた人形は…
（２人）ハッ…
（萌郁）ハアッ…
ハッ
（紅莉栖）ハッ ああ…
those traitors die.
（天王寺）
“裏切り者には死”ってやつだ
Well, once you complete your mission, you also die.
まっ 任務を完了しても消されるが
“犬”って言ったな
You called me a dog, didn't you?
犬なんてもんじゃねえ
家畜さ 俺たちは
I'm worse than a dog.
I'm cattle.
逃げようと思ったこともあった
I've thought of running before,
but I have someone I care about now.
（天王寺）こんな俺にも
大事なものができた
I don't want to get her involved,
そいつを巻き込みたくねえって…
but failure isn't an option.
だがよ　失敗は許されねえ
逃げようとすれば家族も…
If you run, they go after your family.
I failed too,
俺も失敗した
だが 綯は何も知らねえ
but Nae won't know anything...
ハアッ…
as long as I die.
俺さえ死ねば…
Wait—
（岡部）待て
（岡部）ああ…
ああ…
うっ… うう おええっ
（岡部の荒い息）
O-Okabe...
ハッ…
岡部君…
（岡部）ハッ
Okabe...
（萌郁）岡部君…
ハア…
I-I'm sorry.
ご… ごめん
I'm sorry.
ごめん… ね
O-Okabe, his phone!
お… 岡部 携帯！ Ｄメール！
The D-mail!
（紅莉栖）岡部！
（岡部）ハッ
Okabe!
Stop searching for the IBN 5100,and return to stand by.
Do not act under any circumstances.
うん
（岡部）ああっ
あ…
（岡部）萌郁？
Moeka...
Shining Finger
(No Subject)
I won't need the IBN 5100
for a while.
Moeka
（岡部）“必要ない”って…
You don't need it?
Shining Finger
(No Subject)
My boss said to stop looking for it.
Moeka
Yes, this is Urushibara.
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）はい 漆原です
あっ 凶真(きょうま)さん
Kyouma—
えっ ＩＢＮ5100？
What? An IBN 5100?
それなら…
Yes.
ああっ
It's here!
あった
ハア…
ダル
Daru!
Hashida's not here.
橋田なら いないわよ
コミマに行くって言ってたじゃない
He said he was going to Comima.
頼む　俺の願いを聞いてくれ
Please,
hear my request!
（橋田 至(いたる)･紅莉栖）ん？
I see.
（紅莉栖）なるほどね
まゆりの死を避けるには―
To save Mayuri,
we need to get out of this alpha world line
今 私たちがいる
アルファ世界線から抜け出し―
and return to the world line where you didn't sent the first D-mail,
岡部が一番 最初の
Ｄメールを送る前の世界線―
the beta world line.
ベータ世界線に戻るしかない
For that to happen, we have to erase the information from SERN's database.
それにはＳＥＲＮの
データベースにある―
そのデータを消すしかないんだ
（橋田）まゆ氏が死ぬとか
阿万音(あまね)氏が未来人で僕の娘とか
Mayushii dies, and Miss Amane is my daughter from the future.
If that's all bullshit, I think Okarin could become quite the writer.
もし全部 妄想だったら―
オカリン
ラノベ作家になれると思うお
I wish that was true.
そうだったら うれしいが
You believe it, Miss Makise?
（橋田）牧瀬氏 信じるん？
For a hypothesis,
仮説としてはね　できれば
客観的データが欲しいところだけど
if feasible, I'd prefer some reliable, objective data,
but I guess that's impossible.
それは さすがに無理だし
The time leap machine you made worked perfectly.
お前が作ったタイムリープマシンの
出来はガチだった
えっ　そ… そう？
D-Did it?
あ… って 当然でしょ
O-Of course it did!
And...
それに…
ん…
何よ
What?
Nothing.
何でもない
（紅莉栖）何よ
（岡部）何でもないって
What?
I said nothing.
つなぎ終わったお
It's connected.
I need to know the settings, but I can start in ten minutes.
設定いじらないとダメだけど
10分もしないうちに始められる
I'm counting on you, super haker.
頼む　スーパーハカー
スーパーハッカー
Super hacker.
フフッ　最初のＤメールか
The first D-mail, huh?
That's the one where I was stabbed, right?
それって あれでしょ？
私が刺されてたとか何とかっていう
（岡部）うっ
それで あんた
私の体に触ろうとしたりして
Did you try to feel me up or something?
（岡部）これまでのＤメールを
すべて取り消し
By undoing all the D-mails, I'd return to the original world line,
世界線を元に戻す　そこは…
the world line in which SERN doesn't establish a dystopia
ＳＥＲＮが支配するディストピアが
生まれない世界線
まゆりが死なない世界線
and the world line in which Mayuri doesn't die.
そして その世界線では―
However, in that world line...
Makise Kurisu...
牧瀬紅莉栖が―
dies.
死ぬ
～